<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Iran on Aaron Helton</title>
    <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/tags/iran/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iran on Aaron Helton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.aaronhelton.com/tags/iran/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bad History and Ancient Globalization</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/bad-history-and-ancient-globalization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/bad-history-and-ancient-globalization/</guid>
      <description>Earlier, I mentioned that the Sekandar character in Shahnameh was none other than Alexander the Great, and to a large extent the analog holds. There are, however, some interesting anachronisms in Ferdowsi’s text. This is to be expected if you recall that Shahnameh is not a faithful historical document, but instead serves other, more allegorical purposes. Indeed, in earlier parts of the epic, the mists of time obscure familiar reference points such that they just don’t matter that much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shahnameh: Alternative Takes, Update, and Historical Perspective</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/shahnameh-alternative-takes-update-and-historial-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/shahnameh-alternative-takes-update-and-historial-perspective/</guid>
      <description>As time permits, I find myself searching the web for people, places, events, and ideas in Shahnameh. I was pleasantly surprised during such a search to encounter the blog of sci-fi/fantasy author Kate Elliott, who spent much of 2016 reading Shahnameh with another author, Tessa Gratton. They’ve used the opportunity to have a conversation about each of 42 segments (although by the looks of it, they missed a couple of weeks).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shahnameh: A Partial Concordance of Vengeance</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/shahnameh-a-partial-concordance-of-vengeance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/shahnameh-a-partial-concordance-of-vengeance/</guid>
      <description>In my mind, there is something inherently pleasing about a concordance. To those who know me, this is perhaps not a surprising revelation. After all, as a child I spent more time than most thumbing through dictionaries, reading entries at random. We also had a copy of Strong’s Concordance (i.e., The Exhaustive Concordance of the Bible), which, while an admittedly overwhelming tome, nevertheless served as a point of continual attraction to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Like Father Like Son?</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/like-father-like-son/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/like-father-like-son/</guid>
      <description>Illustration of Kay Kavus. Source: http://www.iranicaonline.org/articles/kayanian-v
A recurring motif in Shahnameh is the struggle of generational succession and the effect, especially at the royal scale, of those successions. A multi-generational sacred or epic work can’t really avoid this as a by-product, of course: the Bible itself contains numerous such examples as it details the reigns of the various Israelite kings. In contrast to other works I’ve read that deal with generational succession in some way, Shahnameh concerns itself with the ebb and flow of fortunes that are tied to an individual king’s attitudes, the answer to the overwhelming question: will the son be like the father?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shahnameh: Initial Impressions</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/shahnameh-initial-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/shahnameh-initial-impressions/</guid>
      <description>I’ve almost completed my reading goal for the third day of Shahnameh (which I’m balancing with daily readings of War and Peace, following Brian E. Denton’s daily devotional and mediation series), and I have some initial thoughts. The most immediate impression is also the most superficial, and that’s Dick Davis’s treatment of the subject. In making my selection for an edition to read, I admit I wasn’t looking closely. I might not have selected the Penguin Classics edition had I known it was almost entirely paraphrased prose.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
