<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>philosophy on Aaron Helton</title>
    <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in philosophy on Aaron Helton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.aaronhelton.com/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Struggle Itself</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/the-struggle-itself/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/the-struggle-itself/</guid>
      <description>The Myth of Sisyphus more closely describes the tragedy of the progressive condition than it does the universal human condition. Here I use the term progressive at face value: that is, of or pertaining to progress, and specifically people who hold human progress as a desirable, achievable goal. In this piece, I intend to examine the rationality of pursing human progress when one believes it is impossible.
We can examine human history and development through a few different lenses, each with its faint air of mutual exclusivity hanging over the fact that reality is somewhere in between.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Intention Versus Outcome</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/mapping-intention-versus-outcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/mapping-intention-versus-outcome/</guid>
      <description>The idea for this has been percolating for a while, but it finally managed to escape my head. I do not guarantee it’s complete or usable, but here is my attempt to map out the tension between intention and outcome. Suggestions for improvement are most welcome.
The reason for this map is to examine the landscape within which people operate, especially as it relates to social good. I’ve never been completely comfortable with the idea that “it’s the thought that counts,” because clearly there are situations in which this is not true.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
