<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Greece on Aaron Helton</title>
    <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/tags/greece/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Greece on Aaron Helton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.aaronhelton.com/tags/greece/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thus Spoke Athena</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/thus-spoke-athena/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/thus-spoke-athena/</guid>
      <description>The Odyssey + Midyear Check-in
It took me two months to finish The Odyssey. In terms of pacing and story development, I found the story of Odysseus’s journey home to compare quite favorably to modern novels. In fact, this was something I noticed early on, when Homer introduced numerous scene changes to account for parallel events. True, we can see this in The Iliad to some degree, but the tight focus on Troy and its immediate surrounds didn’t convey the same sense to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sing the Rage 2 the Odyssey</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/sing-the-rage-2-the-odyssey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/sing-the-rage-2-the-odyssey/</guid>
      <description>Sing the Rage 2: The Odyssey Or, Poseidon vs Odysseus
Homer, Odyssey manuscript. Date: 3rd quarter of the 15th century. Source: https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Odyssey-crop.jpg (Public Domain)
I’ve dedicated May to The Odyssey which, in contrast to The Iliad, is not a strict re-read for me. That’s not to say I am unfamiliar with the material, only to say that I’ve never actually read the epic cover to cover before. Despite my late posting, I am in fact reading the work, which concerns ill-fated Odysseus and his very long journey home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sing the Rage: The Iliad</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/sing-the-rage-the-iliad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/sing-the-rage-the-iliad/</guid>
      <description>Triumphant Achilles. Source
My post-Beowulf lull allowed the new month to steal upon me and catch me unawares. I am therefore underprepared this time around and haven’t yet had a chance to put together a proper introduction. This brief post will have to suffice.
The cruellest month is dedicated to The Iliad, one of the two great epics of Classical Greece, attributed to Homer. It tells the story of the final weeks of the ten year long Trojan War, and begins with a focus on a feud between Achilles and Agamemnon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
