<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Literature on Aaron Helton</title>
    <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/tags/literature/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Literature on Aaron Helton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.aaronhelton.com/tags/literature/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Impelled by Fear: Historical Name-dropping</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/impelled-by-fear-historical-name-dropping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/impelled-by-fear-historical-name-dropping/</guid>
      <description>I mentioned in my last post that Aeneid was more visibly self-conscious than Iliad or Odyssey, suggesting that it was the distance afforded by time that was at the root of this. Insofar as there is any regional psychology of the Trojan War, it is only as distilled by Homer and, later, by Virgil. While we have a scholar-backed view of the historicity of the city itself, it is unclear if there was any singular event that could be considered THE Trojan War.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sorrow, Unspeakable Sorrow</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/sorrow-unspeakable-sorrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/sorrow-unspeakable-sorrow/</guid>
      <description>The Aeneid
Not only did I end up delaying my reading of The Aeneid by a month, I have also fallen behind on creating the entry for it. As of today, I have finally made it through the first book, in which Aeneas and his crew, having fled the ruins of Troy, alight on the Libyan coast in search of refuge from the ever-jealous gods who thwart their safe passage to Italy, their destination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thus Spoke Athena</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/thus-spoke-athena/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/thus-spoke-athena/</guid>
      <description>The Odyssey + Midyear Check-in
It took me two months to finish The Odyssey. In terms of pacing and story development, I found the story of Odysseus’s journey home to compare quite favorably to modern novels. In fact, this was something I noticed early on, when Homer introduced numerous scene changes to account for parallel events. True, we can see this in The Iliad to some degree, but the tight focus on Troy and its immediate surrounds didn’t convey the same sense to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sing the Rage 2 the Odyssey</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/sing-the-rage-2-the-odyssey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/sing-the-rage-2-the-odyssey/</guid>
      <description>Sing the Rage 2: The Odyssey Or, Poseidon vs Odysseus
Homer, Odyssey manuscript. Date: 3rd quarter of the 15th century. Source: https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Odyssey-crop.jpg (Public Domain)
I’ve dedicated May to The Odyssey which, in contrast to The Iliad, is not a strict re-read for me. That’s not to say I am unfamiliar with the material, only to say that I’ve never actually read the epic cover to cover before. Despite my late posting, I am in fact reading the work, which concerns ill-fated Odysseus and his very long journey home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fame That Never Dies</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/the-fame-that-never-dies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/the-fame-that-never-dies/</guid>
      <description>A Confluence of Funerary Practices
By Bermicourt — Own work, CC BY-SA 4.0, https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=37502478
Separated by more than a thousand years and at least as many miles, two authors in vastly different cultures nevertheless described strikingly similar treatments for their heroic dead. The earliest of the two appears in Book 7 of The Iliad, where Hector is issuing his challenge for single combat to the Achaeans.
“But if I kill him and Apollo grants me glory,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sing the Rage: The Iliad</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/sing-the-rage-the-iliad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/sing-the-rage-the-iliad/</guid>
      <description>Triumphant Achilles. Source
My post-Beowulf lull allowed the new month to steal upon me and catch me unawares. I am therefore underprepared this time around and haven’t yet had a chance to put together a proper introduction. This brief post will have to suffice.
The cruellest month is dedicated to The Iliad, one of the two great epics of Classical Greece, attributed to Homer. It tells the story of the final weeks of the ten year long Trojan War, and begins with a focus on a feud between Achilles and Agamemnon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad History and Ancient Globalization</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/bad-history-and-ancient-globalization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/bad-history-and-ancient-globalization/</guid>
      <description>Earlier, I mentioned that the Sekandar character in Shahnameh was none other than Alexander the Great, and to a large extent the analog holds. There are, however, some interesting anachronisms in Ferdowsi’s text. This is to be expected if you recall that Shahnameh is not a faithful historical document, but instead serves other, more allegorical purposes. Indeed, in earlier parts of the epic, the mists of time obscure familiar reference points such that they just don’t matter that much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In those days, in those far-off days</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/in-those-days-in-those-far-off-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/in-those-days-in-those-far-off-days/</guid>
      <description>Update on The Epic of Gilgamesh
Source: http://www.mesopotamia.co.uk/gods/explore/bullheav.html
As I am finishing up my reading of The Epic of Gilgamesh, I started this morning on the portion of the Sumerian poems used as the source for Tablet XII. The stark difference in tone and style was immediately noticeable, and this difference, along with the inconsistencies it introduces by way of involving a living Enkidu has caused scholars to consider it an “inorganic appendage” to the main epic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beowulf: Introduction</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/beowulf-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/beowulf-introduction/</guid>
      <description>(Note: Still missing the header image)
Vendel Era Helm on display at the Swedish Museum of National Antiquities.
The epic for March is Beowulf.
When I began thinking about its place among the epics I chose for the year, I thought I might focus on Beowulf’s elegiac quality, something that not all of the epics share, at least not in the same way. On second thought, however, it is clear to me that Gilgamesh also possesses this quality, especially in the Sumerian poems, which refer to him as Bilgames.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shahnameh: Alternative Takes, Update, and Historical Perspective</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/shahnameh-alternative-takes-update-and-historial-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/shahnameh-alternative-takes-update-and-historial-perspective/</guid>
      <description>As time permits, I find myself searching the web for people, places, events, and ideas in Shahnameh. I was pleasantly surprised during such a search to encounter the blog of sci-fi/fantasy author Kate Elliott, who spent much of 2016 reading Shahnameh with another author, Tessa Gratton. They’ve used the opportunity to have a conversation about each of 42 segments (although by the looks of it, they missed a couple of weeks).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>He Who Saw the Deep: the Epic of Gilgamesh</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/he-who-saw-the-deep-the-epic-of-gilgamesh/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/he-who-saw-the-deep-the-epic-of-gilgamesh/</guid>
      <description>(Note: Missing image, currently at /images/gilgamesh.jpeg)
(Note: Learn More section is badly formatted)
Gilgamesh by Union (Wikipedia)
The second book in my Sacer-Epic Reading Journey is The Epic of Gilgamesh. This work, regarded as the earliest known surviving epic, tells the story of its eponymous hero, Gilgamesh, semi-mythical king of Uruk, and his friend Enkidu. It has cast its shadow on numerous later works, including Homer’s epics and the Bible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shahnameh: A Partial Concordance of Vengeance</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/shahnameh-a-partial-concordance-of-vengeance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/shahnameh-a-partial-concordance-of-vengeance/</guid>
      <description>In my mind, there is something inherently pleasing about a concordance. To those who know me, this is perhaps not a surprising revelation. After all, as a child I spent more time than most thumbing through dictionaries, reading entries at random. We also had a copy of Strong’s Concordance (i.e., The Exhaustive Concordance of the Bible), which, while an admittedly overwhelming tome, nevertheless served as a point of continual attraction to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Like Father Like Son?</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/like-father-like-son/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/like-father-like-son/</guid>
      <description>Illustration of Kay Kavus. Source: http://www.iranicaonline.org/articles/kayanian-v
A recurring motif in Shahnameh is the struggle of generational succession and the effect, especially at the royal scale, of those successions. A multi-generational sacred or epic work can’t really avoid this as a by-product, of course: the Bible itself contains numerous such examples as it details the reigns of the various Israelite kings. In contrast to other works I’ve read that deal with generational succession in some way, Shahnameh concerns itself with the ebb and flow of fortunes that are tied to an individual king’s attitudes, the answer to the overwhelming question: will the son be like the father?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shahnameh: Initial Impressions</title>
      <link>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/shahnameh-initial-impressions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aaronhelton.com/blog/shahnameh-initial-impressions/</guid>
      <description>I’ve almost completed my reading goal for the third day of Shahnameh (which I’m balancing with daily readings of War and Peace, following Brian E. Denton’s daily devotional and mediation series), and I have some initial thoughts. The most immediate impression is also the most superficial, and that’s Dick Davis’s treatment of the subject. In making my selection for an edition to read, I admit I wasn’t looking closely. I might not have selected the Penguin Classics edition had I known it was almost entirely paraphrased prose.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
